Shantanu Patil

PROFILE

Android developer focused on delivering top notch, well developed application that provides service to first responders. Offering 4 years of experience in developing health based application using Kotlin, Java, and modern architectures such as MVP and MVVM with strong competency in local storage, coroutines, and API calls. Focused and driven with strength in coding and bug resolution.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kratin 🛮

Lead Technologist

Jul 2021 - present | Nagpur

- Working on complex multimodule project to increase reliability and reusability
- Work on complex gueries to fetch data from SQL database and create correlation in the data
- Understanding the requirements from the client and implement them
- Handling a team to work on deadlines and solve
- · Doing code reviews and making sure that everything is optimized and well written

GlobalLogic Inc. 🗗

Software Engineer (Android Developer)

Jul 2019 - Jul 2021 | Nagpur

- Worked on health base application to deliver new features and work on existing one in MVP architecture
- Handled complex room database queries and Retrofit API calls to display data on UI
- Improved performance by using Dependency Injection (Dagger) and written unit test cases for testing API calls, and local database callbacks
- Worked on content providers to provide data between two different applications
- Delivered Knowledge Training about the application to new members of the team
- Applied various techniques to locate bugs and errors in application.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Kavikulguru Institute of Technology and Science

May 2015 - May 2019 | Ramtek

- · Awarded for Scoring Highest and Second **Highest Marks**
- CGPA: 8.41 (Honors)

SKILLS

Android (MVVM, Coroutines, Jetpack Components, Room, Retrofit, Flows, Unit Testing, Content Providers, Compose)

Programming Languages (Java, Kotlin, Node.js (Basic), Compose (Started Learning))

Other (Application Documentation, Unit Testing, Push Notifications, Crashlytics Integration, Git, Submodules)

Libraries and Architecture (Dagger, Room, Retrofit, RxJava(Basics), MVVM, MVP, MVC)

PROJECTS

Student Revise

Sep 2016 - May 2019

Application for students of Nagpur University for downloading study material which attracted 0.2 million users each semester.

AWARDS

Spot Award

GlobalLogic Inc

Certificate of Appreciation for outstanding performance in a month.